We have learned in the previous video about the binary search three operations.
Now let's try to implement the binary search tree and its operation in sea.
So.
In order to create the binary search tree and we started working with it, we asked Abstract Node and
then send this note.
We put the key, which is F-Type, and you can make it the type car that string or any object or any
primitive data and struck note to the left and right since we are dealing with it.
Three.
So we have this struct note this structure node structure of the note Typekit key that it is or a data
that we are going to insert it inside it and we need a left and right reference.
OK.
This is what we learned in the trees.
We create A. We create a new node method that took into the perimeter the same type of that key that
we have created in the node, and we start by creating a new temp.
We allocate the memory by creating the known reserve, the memory by a new node hole.
10.
And inside this dump, we put a key equal to the item first item in the arguments.
And we initialize them left equal to that price, equal to now.
We initialize the left and the right pointer to the left to null and return tap.
This is how we create a new node in three, and we have learned this before in many cities.
In order traversal, we have seen also this in or traversal in the in order post order and pre-order
video.
So please go back to that three traversal video and to learn more about this method.
Anyway, I am going to say that this an order method.
Took into the perimeter of the route that we had to go at the root node that we are going to work with,
and we start if the route does not equal to null, if route does not equal to null, then traverse left
in order the route to the left.
We are going to use the recursion here in order to pass the route to the left every time until reaching
the root does not the root equal equal to none.
Please go back to the previous video.
In previous videos about the three traversal in order to get deeply.
And digging into that in order to reverse and other order traversal.
Diverse fruit.
We print the and get the key drivers now to that are the same method.
We are going to the northern route to the right there in order traversal in general starts by left,
printing all the left nodes, then printing the route and then going through and printing all the route
to the right.
All the notes to the right.
So left road and right.
Insert A..
And this is the operation that we are going to to implement the sorry for my voice and sorry for coughing
because I am sick with corona.
So and I'm there, I love surgery.
It's like keep, keep learning and keep recording new videos for my lovely students and lovely people
like you.
So insert note we insert we make a new method called insert and we pass into the perimeter.
Two things then note that we are going to insert and into this note return in, you know, if the tree
is empty, OK, if the note equal equal to null, then return, you note.
And we passed the part of me.
We create it, OK, we create it by using than, you know, math here.
Traverse to the right place and insert the note, if key less than the note that we are going to insert
and note key, then go to the left.
Otherwise go to the right.
This is how we insert in the algorithm of inserting because.
Because we are inserting a note that in a binary search, a tree that follows the left sub three values
is less than the root and the rights of values or sub three values is greater than the root.
OK.
For this, we have followed this order.
Like, if that no is the key less than the note that we are going to insert.
So go to the left, otherwise go to the right.
OK.
Now, let's find the in order successor.
Let's find that we have learned in the in the searching operation we need to or when we delete.
In the lead in deletion operation, we need to find the next successor to ensure the success of any
note that we are going to delete.
So I will divide the deletion into two things there in order finding the in order successor minimal
value known.
And we are going to start executing that deletion by replacing this.
Please go back to the deletion operation into the previous video in order to learn more about the three
cases of deletion.
OK.
We create a note current note, and we start finding that left most left leaf and we start jumping the
current cursor to the current left while finding the left mostly.
Now, let's consider that deleting operation, deleting, you know, we create a new method called delete
note, it took into the perimeter of the road and the key that we are going to delete return if the
tree is empty or changing.
If the tree is empty, you can delete anything if I find the note to be deleted.
We need to search for the key so key less than the root key, then go to the left and delete note.
Keep making and keep making this and calling this function in Iraq urgent while maintaining root equal
equal to none.
This is the stopping condition now that a delete note here, because the key less than the root, the
the value of the key of the root.
So we need to go to the left.
As I told you, binary search tree is very important to understand that the concept of it is the left
values of sub.
Three of the last three values is less than the at the root, and that eats up tree values is less than
is greater than everyone else.
Go to the right and delete a note until until reaching the note entirely.
Nope.
No.
If that note is with only one child or no child, a fruit left equal equal to none, then the struck
note them before to root the right and the three to the fruit.
Delete the fruit.
OK.
And return them if route right equal to null, then create a new temp root left and free the root,
delete the root.
If the note has two children, then struck note them minimum value note route to the right and place
the inorder successor in position of the note to be delayed the route give them equal turkey.
So the reference of the route key in the value equal to the stamp a key.
This this is placing the in order successor and we have seen this in the previous video.
So please go back in order to learn about that in order successor.
How to substitute, then order successor with deleted note.
OK, and delete that in order successor.
Deleting the No.
OK, in this delete note, we have a method we have covered the three cases while deleting the note
that it has no children, deleting a note that it is a one child and deleting the note that has two
children by the making attempt note, starting it the minimum value and placing the insert in order
a successor in the position to the note to be deleted and then deleting the in order a successor and
placing it.
OK.
This is how we delete the note.
I told you it is more complex.
It's the most complex operation in binary secretary, which is deletion, and it has three cases.
Please go back and then the previous video in order to learn more, and we need to create a driver code
that test our code in the main so struct nodes wrote the root equal to insert root equal eight value
eight.
So creating the root and eight and inserting root three, one, six, seven, 10 and 14 and four.
OK, we are inserting them now in order traversal.
We are printing that in order to the reversal after after deleting the ten.
So go and execute delete through.
Then in order traversal here is in order root.
So we are printing this.
I want from you to put this code into your C compiler and I want from you to give me the result and
give me the solution of this exercise and the output of this exercise.
Enter comments below.
In order to discuss more and more, and I want from you also to play with this code and add your numbers,
nodes and delete operation or their operation and inserting operation.
And please give me the results in the comments below.
Let's go to the implementation and if a binary search tree and a.